MOTHER, AGE 52, STABBED TO DEATH
POLICE SEEK MISSING SON
UNKNOWN CALLER
Hello?
Silent again?
Who is this?
Did you call me yesterday?
What?
Thank God! It really was you, Satoru.
I see the resemblance to your mother.
Do you remember me? I'm Sawada.
I worked with your mother
in TV Ishikari's News Division.
I'm a freelance writer now.
Don't worry. I haven't called the police.
And I'm also not the one
who killed your mother.
You don't suspect me?
Of course not. A woman like that
could never have raised a murderer.
What happened?
That girl must have vital information.
-He wanted to keep her silent.
-Yes.
We found her fingerprints
on the weapon used to kill the mother.
After getting her to help kill his mother,
he no longer needed her.
So, he was getting rid of her.
No.
That's not it at all.
Satoru.
I have to tell you something.
The day Sachiko was killed,
I got a call from her.
She wanted to talk about
the serial kidnappings and murders
that happened 18 years ago.
Hello, it's been a long time.
It's Sachiko Fujinuma.
Look.
It's about the kidnappings
from 18 years ago.
She said she might know
who the real killer was.
Then who...was the real killer?
She didn't tell me because
she wasn't sure about the name.
But...
I feel like we finally found it.
A tiny crack in the killer's
meticulously-covered tracks.
You should read this.
It's the report I compiled
on the crimes from 18 years ago.
Thank you.
MAN IN HIS 20S ARRESTED
ANOTHER GIRL MURDERED
KAYO HINAZUKI
AYA NAKANISHI
BOY GOES MISSING
MISSING BOY, HIROMI SUGITA
SUSPECT IN CHILD MURDERS
MALE FOOD SERVICE EMPLOYEE ARRESTED
The footprints left around
the storage unit
matched the rubber boots used by Jun
Shiratori's workplace, Shiratori Foods.
He took her to an industrial freezer
and sprayed her down
to freeze her quickly.
SHIRATORI SUSPECTED IN CHILD MURDERS
KILLINGS IN INDUSTRIAL FREEZER
Yuuki would never do something like this!
SHIRATORI FOODS
It's my fault.
If I'd only...
insisted on his innocence more...
Yuuki isn't the killer!
-Yuuki isn't the killer!
-The killer's been caught!
-No! Yuuki isn't the killer!
-Satoru! Forget about all of this!
Satoru...
it's not that Sachiko didn't believe you.
Make them forget about the killings?
That means erasing their memories, too.
I know it's wrong.
But I still want the children to forget
that any of this ever happened.
She just wanted to ease your burden.
We just tried to make it easier...
for you kids to forget about it.
SHIRATORI REARRESTED IN CONNECTION
TO HIROMI'S MURDER
In any case, Jun Shiratori had no alibi,
so I don't think it would've mattered.
-Hey.
-Yes?
-You go grab something to eat first.
-Okay.
UNKNOWN CALLER
Hello?
Satoru?
Thank goodness, you kept it on.
Airi?
Are you okay?
Yeah. Anyway, I want to talk about
the killer.
Can we meet?
Don't worry, Airi promises to come alone.
Okay, we'll meet under the overpass.
Thank you, I'll be right there.
I could've just asked her
about the killer over the phone.
But...
Satoru, I'm here!
Sorry I'm late, I had to lose
the detectives tailing me.
It's okay.
I'm ashamed to admit I thought
it might be a trap set by the police.
I said it aloud.
Well, you have to!
You're a fugitive, after all.
So...
I actually saw the killer's face.
-Is it someone you know?
-No, nobody I knew.
But I feel like I just met him recently.
Probably at the restaurant.
At the restaurant?
Have I met him, too, then?
Who is it?
Satoru!
I understand how you feel,
but don't do anything reckless.
Yeah.
I'm like the Grim Reaper.
I'm trying to do the right thing,
but the more I do, the more misery I bring
the people involved.
That's not true.
Everything in front of us
is still in progress.
This isn't anywhere near over,
and nobody knows how it will end.
Dispatch. Target has been located
under the overpass.
-You are Satoru Fujinuma?
-Suspect detained at 4:50 p.m.
You're under arrest for murder, attempted
murder, and breaking and entering.
Satoru didn't do it.
I'm sorry, Satoru!
I led the police right to you.
Even though I promised to come alone.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, this is all my fault!
Airi, you're wrong.
I can keep going because I know
you still believe in me.
Satoru...
Thank you, Airi.
I'm glad I trusted you.
I'm really glad...
I met you.
FEBRUARY 29TH (MONDAY)
I'm back...
in the year 1988
again...
Satoru.
Did you read the book I lent you
about two weeks ago?
Poe's The Man who Switched Places?
Sorry, I haven't finished it yet.
You got a second, Satoru?
I never lent you any book.
What?
Who are you, exactly?
You've been different ever since the day
I noticed you looking at Hinazuki.
Maybe I only noticed because
I knew about Hinazuki's bruises, too.
This is not good. I got too wrapped up
with Hinazuki to cover myself.
I might be able to see the situation,
but I'm bad with taking action.
But there you were
getting involved right in front of me.
The old Satoru would've never done that.
Tell me, who are you?
I'm...
I'm a defender of justice.
I mean...
that's what I want to be.
I guess I have to tell Kenya the truth.
Kenya... Hinazuki is going to be killed.
I saw her after she'd been abused.
If it were at night,
Hinazuki would've been dead.
So, next time,
I'm going to stop it.
Satoru, you're already
a defender of justice.
Hey, Mom.
You're still awake?
I just want you to remember.
You can actually...
make it to Ueno on one train.
What are you talking about?
Good night.
This is when it matters.
MARCH 2ND (THURSDAY)
Happy birthday!
-Here's your presents.
-We're giving presents already?
-Here, here's mine. Here you go.
-Thanks!
Here you go.
It's today.
My actions today will change the future.
It's so good.
I forgot something at school.
I'll be right back.
-You're going this late?
-Yeah.
Be careful, all right?
SHIRATORI FOODS INC.
What? Who did this?!
DIE
-Jun, call the police!
-Okay!
Good. Now the police will be able to give
Yuuki an alibi for tonight.
DEFENDING YOURSELF
WITH HOUSEHOLD OBJECTS
HOW TO MAKE A STUN GUN
FROM A DISPOSABLE CAMERA.
1. DISASSEMBLE THE CAMERA
5. PUT IN THE FLASH BUTTON
AND YOU'RE DONE!
If I only get rid of you...
Hinazuki won't have to die!
Try to calm down.
I couldn't help feeling
that Hinazuki was in danger today.
Come talk to me, then.
You're not alone in this anymore.
That's it.
Kenya, I need your help.
You should take this one.
Yeah, right, I'm not falling for that.
Is it almost time to call it a night?
Let's clean up.
Okay.
-Thank you for having us today.
-Thank you very much.
Thank you!
-Be careful, now.
-Yes.
-Thank you for having me.
-Take care.
-Thanks for coming.
-All right, I'll go walk Hinazuki home.
-Okay.
Hinazuki.
Would you be okay
if I kidnapped you now?
You stupid?
Yeah. That's why this was
all I could come up with.
Here we are.
What is this?
It used to be the club room
for Izumi's ice hockey club.
It's just used for storage now.
Let's go.
Satoru!
-Kenya!
-Help me get the stove inside.
Okay. Why don't you go inside
and wait for us, Hinazuki?
It's all the way in the back.
It came together nicely, huh?
Yeah, we did good.
Well, we should get going.
Bye. I'll be back tomorrow.
Thank you.
Satoru, Kenya.
You don't have to thank us.
We're friends.
Don't worry, Kayo.
We promise we'll protect you.
See you.
Thanks, Kenya.
It's too early for that.
We haven't gotten to the tricky part.
Yeah.
-You finally called her Kayo.
-What? No, I didn't.
-You did.
-Did not.
You just didn't notice.
-I didn't call her that.
-You did, too!
Maybe I did...
-Haruko Nomura.
-Here.
-Kaori Hasebe.
-Koichi Hamada.
-Here.
Kayo Hinazuki.
I guess Kayo is late again.
Satoru Fujinuma.
Here.
-Kazuma Horiguchi.
-Here.
-Yuko Matsumoto.
-Misato Yanagihara.
-Here.
-Ami Yuuki.
Naoki Watanabe.
Hello, I'm Yashiro, a teacher
at Mikoto Elementary School.
Could you connect me with the person
in charge of child abuse cases?
I'm sorry I roped you into this, too,
Hiromi.
I'm just glad anybody would want my help.
Besides, I'd just be all alone in my house
until 8:00.
I'm sorry to you, too, Kayo.
For keeping you locked in here.
No. I've never had so much fun.
I'm glad I got up the courage to come.
So, what's going to happen in the end?
Don't worry.
-I'll take the responsibility for this.
-You stupid?
If we just say this was my idea...
and you all just helped me...
then nobody will get into trouble!
That's true.
We never thought of that, huh?
Satoru?
Subtitle translation by
ZENSHO YAMAMOTO